Leticia Coelho

Software Engineer

Profile

I graduated as a Telecommunications Engineer. I have experience in developing web applications and industrial applications, developing firmware to get real-world data and web software to render the data (IoT). My main skills are related to creating maintainable web applications following good software engineering practices.

Specialties: Web applications, Software architecture, Industrial applications

Experience

Community Leader and Content Creator

Community Leader | BeeStrong Code | 03/2021 - present

As a community Leader, I'm working on the BeeStrong Community to give access to tech careers for women and non-gender people, creating articles, tutorials, classes, and mentorship

Main technologies: computer engineering concepts, Git, Github, soft-skills, python, java, javascript.

Content Creator | Engineer Rabbit | 06/2019 - present

As a content creator, I am responsible for creating articles, blog posts, tutorials and mentorships. Always using analogies and creative posts to teach computer engineering concepts in an easy and illustrated way.

Main technologies: computer engineering concepts, soft-skills.

Software Engineer | ArcTouch | 04/2021 - present

PROJECT

SMALL PROJECT DESCRIPTION

Main technologies: React, Python, PyTest, Gfriend, Javascript

PROJECT

SMALL PROJECT DESCRIPTION

Main technologies: Wagtail CMS, Python, MySql, NextJs, Storybook

PROJECT

SMALL PROJECT DESCRIPTION

Main technologies: Angular 1.0, Custom components, Javascript ES6, Jest, Python, Django.

PROJECT

SMALL PROJECT DESCRIPTION

Main technologies: NextJs, xStates, Javascript, Jest.

PROJECT

SMALL PROJECT DESCRIPTION

Main technologies: React, Javascript, Jest, Clean Code, Clean architecture.

PROJECT

SMALL PROJECT DESCRIPTION

Main technologies: Vue, Javascript, Node.js, MongoDB, Parse Server, PayPal, Clean Code, Clean architecture.

Full-Stack Software Developer | Involves | 09/2019 - 04/2021

Involves stage | Involves

Involves Stage is a trade-marketing solution. With the tool it is possible to manage your team in the field, monitor reports and generate insights, in order to increase productivity and sales.

I worked to solve bugs, decoupling software, improvements in the implementation of communication (websocket) implementing new communication requirements between the mobile and web applications. Work into the creation of a new import architecture feature.

Main technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, GIT, AngularJS, ReactJS, jQuery, REST API, Clean Code, Clean architecture, MVC.

Full-Stack Software Developer Consultant | Azuritta | 04/2020 - 06/2020

Condominium bills | Azuritta

A web platform to verify reports associated with condominium accounting in order to optimize the work performed by the administrative team.

Main technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Auth2, ReactJS, CSS, HTML, MongoDb, MySql.

Full-Stack Software Architect and Developer Consultant | Ciclix | 09/2019 - 10/2019

Object Traceability | Ciclix

Indoor IoT infrastructure for location of hospital materials. Reaching the goal of delivering the communication infrastructure between firmware and servers, through the specialized indoor location service for healthcare.

Main technologies: Project architecture, documentation and project definition, *Middleware*, microservices, *SAAS*, *Beacons*, *Gateway BLE*, *ODOO*, *Python*, *RFID*, *FIND3*, *Firebase*, *MongoDB*, *AWS*, *Docker*.

Full-Stack Software Architect and Developer | Macnica DHW | 10/2018 - 09/2019

Beta of Temporary Grounding Control | CGTI Institute

Project with the objective of controlling and supervising installed temporary grounds, using IoT and Smart Mesh, and demonstrating results through a web page and through the Supervisory System (SCADA). This project generated a patent for the company CGTI Taesa.

Main technologies: Project architecture, Embedded systems, Smart mesh, FreeRTOS, Bootstrap, Modbus RTU, Internet of Things, microsservice, HTML, Python, Flask, JQuery, relational database, communication protocol, API, Industry 4.0, Telecommunications.

Undergraduate Intern | Soma | 11/2017 - 09/2018

Remote experiment | Soma

Main technologies: Arduino Board, C++, HTML, CSS, Python, MongoDB, Flask, jQuery, APIRestfull, WebRTC, MQTT, HTTP, Websocket, Cloud.

Didactic Bench - Programmable Logic Controller | SENAI MT

Its main purpose is to program the PLC to control and monitor motors, using various switches and indicator LEDs, adapted for use in the laboratory. I developed the kit and trained SENAI teachers to use this didactic kit.

Main technologies: Electronics, Industrial processes, HMI, V20, G120, CLP 1214C Siemens, industrial communication (Modbus, Profibus, Profinet, OPC, RS485), 4.0 Industry

Didactic Kit - Motors and transformers | SENAI MT

Allows electrical connection with starting devices for three-phase and single-phase electric motors. I developed the kit and trained SENAI teachers to use this didactic kit.

Main technologies: Electronics, Industrial processes

Didactic Kit - Industrial Communication Networks | SENAI MT

Programming of PLC, HMI and frequency inverter. Industrial communication between PLC, HMI and frequency inverter. Command and activation of induction motors. I developed the kit and trained SENAI teachers to use this didactic kit.

Main technologies: Electronics, Industrial processes, HMI, CLP 1214C Siemens, industrial communication (Modbus, Profibus, Prof

Didactic Kit - Instrumentation Teaching | SENAI MT

Instrumentation study, Centrifugal pump activation, pneumatic valve, reservoir level control, PLC control and programming, HMI and frequency inverter. I developed the kit and trained SENAI teachers to use this didactic kit.

Main technologies: Electronics, Industrial processes, HMI, V20, G120, CLP 1214C Siemens, industrial communication (Modbus, Profibus, Profinet, OPC, RS485), 4.0 Industry

Didactic Kit - Frequency Inverter | SENAI MT

Drive and programming the frequency inverter; Motor activation, monitoring and control; Activation of keys, relays and leds. I developed the kit and trained SENAI teachers to use this didactic kit.

Main technologies: Electronics, V20, industrial communication (Modbus, Profibus, Profinet, OPC), 4.0 Industry, Industrial processes.

Research Student | Superior Institute of Engineering of Porto | 03/2017 - 07/2017

VISIR Project | Propicie program

It aims to define, develop and evaluate a set of educational modules comprising hands-on, virtual, and remote experiments, the latter supported by a remote lab named Virtual Instruments Systems In Reality (VISIR).

Main technologies: National instruments, VISIR+, HTML, CSS, PHP, HTTP, MariaDB, SQL, Remote Laboratories, Remote applications.

Research Student | Federal Institute of Santa Catarina | 02/2014 - 03/2017

MedBox | IFSC

The MedBox project is an electronic medication box that contains the necessary hardware to detect events, trigger and control activities related to the user's medication intake. I worked as a Software engineer studying and implementing the minimal valuable project.

Main technologies: Embedded Systems, C, C++, HTTP, Wi-fi, Bluetooth, Communications, Protocol, Product development, Internet of Things, Intel Galileo Gen 2 and Arduino Board.

Education

Federal Institute of Santa Catarina (IFSC) | 2013 - 2019

B.S., Telecommunications Engineer

Other Courses or Certifications

Awards and Contest

2017 Second place at the IFSC Innovative Ideas Contest (7.000,00 BRL grand) - Brazil.

2017 Final step at the Sinapses of Innovation Contest (Innovation training) - Brazil.

2017 Final step at The best of Innovation Contest (Innovation training) - Brazil.

2017 Final step at Intel Embedded Systems Competition - Brazil.

Grants

Scholarship Holder of PROPICIE (IFSC International Student Exchange Program) from March 2017 to July. €3,500.00.

Courses

2015 - Internet of Things - Forum internacional de Software Livre - 60 Hrr

2016 - SBESC - School of Embedded Systems - SBC - 60 Hrs

2017 - Empretec - Sebrae - 63 Hrs

2017 - Machine Learning / IOT - The developers conference - 16 Hrs

2018 - Introduction to space technologies - INPE - 126 Hrs

2018 - Application of Machine Learning Techniques Using R - IFSC - 3 Hrs

2018 - Matlab - IFSC - 66 Hrs

2018 - Machine Learning / IOT - The developers conference - 16 Hrs

2020 - Udemy: React.

2022 - Spark AR Meta official - in progress

2022 - Solutions Architect - Linux tips - In progress

Courses and Conference organization

2015 ~ 2016 - Teacher - Basic Arduino workshops, São José, Santa Catarina - BR.

2016 - Teacher - Workshop Business model canvas Básico - São José, SC.

2016 - Teacher - Brainstorming Básico - São José, SC.

2017 - Teacher - Django Girls, São José, Santa Catarina - BR.

2017 - Organizing committee - The developers Conference, Florianópolis.

2018 - Teacher - Siemens Tia Portal V15 Tool - SENAI Institute - Cuiabá, MT.

2019 - Technical and Business Mentor - Hackathon Agroup - Vitória da Conquista,

BA.

2019 - Technical and Business Mentor - Startup Weekend Woman - Florianópolis,

SC.

2019 - Speaker - ENTIDV - Florianópolis, SC.

2020 - Volunteer Technical Mentor - Conecta Startup Brazil, Brazil.

2021 - Speaker - O triângulo invertido do front-end - The developers Conference, Florianópolis.

- 2021 Speaker Desmistificando o Tecniquês The developers Conference, Florianópolis.
- 2021 Speaker Processos seletivos na área tech: Por onde começar? Google Developers Group
- 2021 Speaker Entendendo os impostores que dificultam os testes unitários Womakers Code.
- 2021 Speaker Como garantir resultados amigáveis para pessoas que usam ferramentas assistivas? Arctouch
- 2021 Speaker Como é trabalhar em uma empresa americana e falar inglês no dia-a-dia? Arctouch
- 2021 Speaker Programação inclusiva: Como garantir resultados amigaveis para pessoas que usam ferramentas assistivas? ArcTouch
- 2021 Speaker Inclusão e diversidade na tecnologia Data Master
- 2022 Speaker Ferramentas e dicas para arrasar no mercado de trabalho Elas Computação
- 2022 Speaker Mulheres que fazem a diferença O matuto programador
- 2022 Organizing committee and speaker Wonder Tech Dev brazillian community
- 2022 Teacher Git e GitHub BeeStrong Code

Publications

- COELHO, L. A. ;FERTIG, K.S.;FERTIG, K.S. TKmed Medication aid system. Extended abstract. In: VI Brazilian Symposium on Computing Systems Engineering 2016, João Pessoa, Paraíba.
- 2. COELHO, L. A. ;FERTIG, K.S.;FERTIG, K.S. TKmed Sistema de auxílio à medicação. Abstract. In: Mostra Científico Cultural 2016, São José, Santa Catarina.
- 3. BRANCO, M.V.; COELHO, L. A. ;ALVES, G. R. Differentiating simulations and real (remote) experiments. Full paper. In: 5th International Conference on Technological Ecosystems for Enhancing Multiculturality, 2017, Cádiz, Espanha.
- BRANCO, M.V.; COELHO, L. A. ;ALVES, G.R. Aspectos de diferenciação entre laboratórios remotos e simuladores. Full paper. In: Cobenge 2017, 2017, Joinville, Santa Catarina.
- BRANCO, M.V.; COELHO, L. A. ;ALVES, G.R. Estudo Comparativo entre Laboratórios Remotos e Simuladores. Chapter 16. In: TICAI 2017 - TICs para el Aprendizaje de la Ingeniería. ISBN 978-84-8158-774-6 ©IEEE, Sociedad de Educación: Cápitulos Español y Portugués.
- 6. ALMEIDA, D.P.;, ABELHA, M., ARPINO, C., COELHO, L., CORRÊA, M., SARAIVA, J.P., MATTIELLO-FRANCISCO, F. Simulação da operação e comunicação de uma carga útil baseada na Sonda de Langmuir com o OBC do NanosatC-Br2. Full paper. In: 9° Workshop on Space Engineering and Technology, 2018, São José dos Campos, São Paulo.